Finding Aid for American Right of Way Association. Michigan Chapter, No. 7 records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
American Right of Way Association. Michigan Chapter, No. 7. records
1954-1983
American Right of Way Association. Michigan Chapter, No. 7.
85603 Bm 2
Organization of people engaged in right of way work. Correspondence, constitution and bylaws, minutes of meetings, treasurer's reports, membership applications, and other material
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
8 linear feet
The records were deposited by the organization (donor no. 5021 ) in periodic accessions.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michigan chapter of the American Right of Way Association, an organization first formed in southern California in 1934 to provide training for individuals involved in right-of-way activities, to develop professional networks, and to educate the public on right of way issues. The Michigan Chapter was formally organized in 1954.
The records of the American Right of Way Association. Michigan Chapter, No. 7 include correspondence, constitution and bylaws, minutes of meetings, treasurer's reports, membership applications, and other material.
Subjects:
Right of way--United States.; Traffic engineering--United States.; Transportation--United States.
- By-Laws and Minutes
  - By-Laws, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Meetings
    - 1954-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1966 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Executive Board, December 1967 (Box 1)
- Organizational records
  (arranged largely by date)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence of National Officers, 1959 (Box 1)
  - National Liaison Committee Information, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Internal Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Internal Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of National Officers, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Programs, 1960 (Box 2)
  - National and Regional Seminars, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with other Chapters, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Utility-Liaison Committee, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and Minutes (D.G. Warren), 1961 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - January 1961-July 1962 (Box 2)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 2)
  - Utility-Liaison Committee Correspondence and Minutes, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Secretary's Correspondence
    - R.R. Cunningham, 1962 (Box 2)
    - W.L. Reid, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Minutes of Board Meetings and Treasurer's Reports (Box 3)
  - Liaison Committee Correspondence and Minutes, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Minutes of Executive Board, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Roster, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Liaison Committee Correspondence and Minutes, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Progress Report, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Membership Lists, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - National News Bulletins and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Magazine Space Contracts, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - National Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Bills and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Roster and Dues, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Member Resignations, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Liaison Committee Correspondence & Minutes, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Photographs of Past Presidents, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Program of San Diego Meeting, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Liaison Committee Materials, 1966 (Box 4)
  - National Committee Materials, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Approved Applicants, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1966 (Box 4)
  - National Newsletters, 1966 (Box 4)
  - National News Bulletins and Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Member Resignations, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Dues and Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Change of Address Letters, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Roster Sheets, 1967 (Box 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1967 (Box 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Current National Letters (undated) (Box 5)
  - Membership Report, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Printed Contracts (undated) (Box 5)
  - Capita and Magazine Assessment
    - July-December 1966 (Box 5)
    - January-June 1967 (Box 5)
  - Membership Report
    - September –, December 1967 (Box 5)
    - December 1966 (Box 5)
  - Income Tax, 1963-1967 (Box 5)
  - Roster
    - 1966-1967 (Box 5)
    - Information, (undated) (Box 5)
    - 1968 (Box 5)
  - Addressograph Machine, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Regional Report (Box 5)
- Other materials and later additions
  - Changes in Membership Status, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Membership Applications
    - 1969 (Box 5)
    - A-E, 1954 (Box 5)
    - F-M, 1954 (Box 5)
    - N-Z, 1954 (Box 5)
  - National Chapter Activities, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Charter -- City of Northville (Box 5)
  - An Analysis of Right of Way Educational Needs, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Liaison Committee Materials, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Excess Property Negotiations (Box 5)
  - Utility-Liaison Committee Minutes (Box 5)
  - Advertising for the American Right of Way Magazine (Box 5)
  - Roster, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Minutes
    - 1968 (Box 5)
    - 1969 (Box 5)
  - Financial Records, 1970-1974 (Box 6)
  - 1975-1978 (Box 7)
    (lacking 1978)
  - 1984 Accession: Records (unprocessed), circa 1978-1984 (Box 8)
  - Accession: 2 Notebooks (unprocessed), 1985 (Box 8)